[
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements should be used to obtain a remainder after dividing 3.14 by 2.1 ?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "rem = 3.14 % 2.1;",
        "b": "rem = modf(3.14, 2.1);",
        "c": "rem = fmod(3.14, 2.1);",
        "d": "Remainder cannot be obtain in floating point division.",
        "answer": "rem = fmod(3.14, 2.1);"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the types of linkages?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Internal and External",
        "b": "External, Internal and None",
        "c": "External and None",
        "d": "Internal",
        "answer": "External, Internal and None"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following special symbol allowed in a variable name?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "* (asterisk)",
        "b": "| (pipeline)",
        "c": "- (hyphen)",
        "d": "_ (underscore)",
        "answer": "_ (underscore)"
    },
    {
        "question": "\t\r\nIs there any difference between following declarations?\r\n1 :\textern int fun();\r\n2 :\tint fun();",
        "a": "Both are identical",
        "b": "No difference, except extern int fun(); is probably in another file",
        "c": "int fun(); is overrided with extern int fun();",
        "d": "None of these",
        "answer": "No difference, except extern int fun(); is probably in another file"
    },
    {
        "question": "How would you round off a value from 1.66 to 2.0?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "ceil(1.66)",
        "b": "floor(1.66)",
        "c": "roundup(1.66)",
        "d": "roundto(1.66)",
        "answer": "ceil(1.66)"
    },
    {
        "question": "By default a real number is treated as a\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "float",
        "b": "double",
        "c": "long double",
        "d": "far double",
        "answer": "double"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not user defined data type?\r\n1 :struct book\r\n{\r\n    char name[10];\r\n    float price;\r\n    int pages;\r\n};\r\n2 :long int l = 2.35;\r\n3 :enum day {Sun, Mon, Tue, Wed};\r\n",
        "a": "1",
        "b": "2",
        "c": "3",
        "d": "Both 1 and 2",
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is the following statement a declaration or definition?\r\nextern int i;",
        "a": "Declaration",
        "b": "Definition",
        "c": "Function",
        "d": "Error",
        "answer": "Declaration"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify which of the following are declarations\r\n1 :\textern int x;\r\n2 :\tfloat square ( float x ) { ... }\r\n3 :\tdouble pow(double, double);\r\n",
        "a": "1",
        "b": "2",
        "c": "1 and 3",
        "d": "3",
        "answer": "1 and 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the following program where is the variable a getting defined and where it is getting declared?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    extern int a;\r\n    printf(\"%d\\n\", a);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}\r\nint a=20;",
        "a": "extern int a is declaration, int a = 20 is the definition",
        "b": "int a = 20 is declaration, extern int a is the definition",
        "c": "int a = 20 is definition, a is not defined",
        "d": "a is declared, a is not defined",
        "answer": "extern int a is declaration, int a = 20 is the definition"
    },
    {
        "question": "When we mention the prototype of a function?",
        "a": "Defining",
        "b": "Declaring",
        "c": "Prototyping",
        "d": "Calling",
        "answer": "Declaring"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the output of the program given below ?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    enum status { pass, fail, atkt};\r\n    enum status stud1, stud2, stud3;\r\n    stud1 = pass;\r\n    stud2 = atkt;\r\n    stud3 = fail;\r\n    printf(\"%d, %d, %d\\n\", stud1, stud2, stud3);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "0, 1, 2",
        "b": "1, 2, 3",
        "c": "0, 2, 1",
        "d": "1, 3, 2",
        "answer": "0, 2, 1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program in 16 bit platform (Turbo C under DOS)?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    extern int i;\r\n    i = 20;\r\n    printf(\"%d\\n\", sizeof(i));\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "2",
        "b": "4",
        "c": "vary from compiler",
        "d": "Linker Error : Undefined symbol 'i'",
        "answer": "Linker Error : Undefined symbol 'i'"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    extern int a;\r\n    printf(\"%d\\n\", a);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}\r\nint a=20;",
        "a": "20",
        "b": "0",
        "c": "Garbage Value",
        "d": "Error",
        "answer": "20"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the output of the program in Turbo C (in DOS 16-bit OS)?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    char *s1;\r\n    char far *s2;\r\n    char huge *s3;\r\n    printf(\"%d, %d, %d\\n\", sizeof(s1), sizeof(s2), sizeof(s3));\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "2, 4, 6",
        "b": "4, 4, 2",
        "c": "2, 4, 4",
        "d": "2, 2, 2",
        "answer": "2, 4, 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the output of the program\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    struct emp\r\n    {\r\n        char name[20];\r\n        int age;\r\n        float sal;\r\n    };\r\n    struct emp e = {\"Tiger\"};\r\n    printf(\"%d, %f\\n\", e.age, e.sal);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "0, 0.000000",
        "b": "Garbage values",
        "c": "Error",
        "d": "None of above",
        "answer": "0, 0.000000"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint X=40;\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int X=20;\r\n    printf(\"%d\\n\", X);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "20",
        "b": "40",
        "c": "Error",
        "d": "No Output",
        "answer": "20"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the output of the program\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int x = 10, y = 20, z = 5, i;\r\n    i = x < y < z;\r\n    printf(\"%d\\n\", i);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "0",
        "b": "1",
        "c": "Error",
        "d": "None of these",
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the output of the program\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    extern int fun(float);\r\n    int a;\r\n    a = fun(3.14);\r\n    printf(\"%d\\n\", a);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}\r\nint fun(int aa)\r\n{\r\n    return (int)++aa;\r\n}",
        "a": "3",
        "b": "3.14",
        "c": "Compile Error",
        "d": "4",
        "answer": "Compile Error"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the output of the program\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int a[5] = {2, 3};\r\n    printf(\"%d, %d, %d\\n\", a[2], a[3], a[4]);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "Garbage Values",
        "b": "2, 3, 3",
        "c": "3, 2, 2",
        "d": "0, 0, 0",
        "answer": "0, 0, 0"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    union a\r\n    {\r\n        int i;\r\n        char ch[2];\r\n    };\r\n    union a u;\r\n    u.ch[0] = 3;\r\n    u.ch[1] = 2;\r\n    printf(\"%d, %d, %d\\n\", u.ch[0], u.ch[1], u.i);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "3, 2, 515",
        "b": "515, 2, 3",
        "c": "3, 2, 5",
        "d": "None of these",
        "answer": "3, 2, 515"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the following program how long will the for loop get executed?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int i=5;\r\n    for(;scanf(\"%s\", &i); printf(\"%d\\n\", i));\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "The for loop would not get executed at all",
        "b": "The for loop would get executed only once",
        "c": "The for loop would get executed 5 times",
        "d": "The for loop would get executed infinite times",
        "answer": "The for loop would get executed infinite times"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int X=40;\r\n    {\r\n        int X=20;\r\n        printf(\"%d \", X);\r\n    }\r\n    printf(\"%d\\n\", X);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "40 40",
        "b": "20 40",
        "c": "20",
        "d": "Error",
        "answer": "20 40"
    },
    {
        "question": "Point out the error in the following program (if it is compiled with Turbo C compiler).\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    display();\r\n    return 0;\r\n}\r\nvoid display()\r\n{\r\n    printf(\"NepalBIX.com\");\r\n}",
        "a": "No error",
        "b": "display() doesn't get invoked",
        "c": "display() is called before it is defined",
        "d": "None of these",
        "answer": "display() is called before it is defined"
    },
    {
        "question": "Point out the error in the following program.\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    void v = 0;\r\n\r\n    printf(\"%d\", v);\r\n\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "Error: Declaration syntax error 'v' (or) Size of v is unknown or zero.",
        "b": "Program terminates abnormally.",
        "c": "error",
        "d": "None of these.",
        "answer": "Error: Declaration syntax error 'v' (or) Size of v is unknown or zero."
    },
    {
        "question": "Point out the error in the following program.\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nstruct emp\r\n{\r\n    char name[20];\r\n    int age;\r\n};\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    emp int xx;\r\n    int a;\r\n    printf(\"%d\\n\", &a);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "Error: in printf",
        "b": "Error: in emp int xx;",
        "c": "No error.",
        "d": "None of these.",
        "answer": "Error: in emp int xx;"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is correct about err used in the declaration given below?\r\n\r\n typedef enum error { warning, test, exception } err;",
        "a": "It is a typedef for enum error.",
        "b": "It is a variable of type enum error.",
        "c": "The statement is erroneous.",
        "d": "It is a structure.",
        "answer": "It is a typedef for enum error."
    },
    {
        "question": "Point out the error in the following program.\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int (*p)() = fun;\r\n    (*p)();\r\n    return 0;\r\n}\r\nint fun()\r\n{\r\n    printf(\"NepalBix.com\\n\");\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "Error: in int(*p)() = fun;",
        "b": "Error: fun() prototype not defined",
        "c": "No error",
        "d": "None of these",
        "answer": "Error: fun() prototype not defined"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the declaration is correct?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "int length;",
        "b": "char int;",
        "c": "int long;",
        "d": "float double;",
        "answer": "int length;"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following operations are INCORRECT?",
        "a": "int i = 35; i = i%5;",
        "b": "short int j = 255; j = j;",
        "c": "long int k = 365L; k = k;",
        "d": "float a = 3.14; a = a%3;",
        "answer": "float a = 3.14; a = a%3;"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following correctly represents a long double constant?",
        "a": "6.68",
        "b": "6.68L",
        "c": "6.68f",
        "d": "6.68LF",
        "answer": "6.68L"
    },
    {
        "question": "A long double can be used if range of a double is not enough to accommodate a real number.",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "A float is 4 bytes wide, whereas a double is 8 bytes wide.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the definition of the external variable occurs in the source file before its use in a particular function, then there is no need for an extern declaration in the function.",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Size of short integer and long integer can be verified using the sizeof() operator.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Range of double is -1.7e-38 to 1.7e+38 (in 16 bit platform - Turbo C under DOS)\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "Size of short integer and long integer would vary from one platform to another.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Range of float id -2.25e+308 to 2.25e+308\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is there any difference in the following declarations?\r\nint myfun(int arr[]);\r\nint myfun(arr[20]);",
        "a": "Yes",
        "b": "No",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "Yes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Suppose a program is divided into three files f1, f2 and f3, and a variable is defined in the file f1 but used in files f2 and f3. In such a case would we need the extern declaration for the variables in the files f2 and f3?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Yes",
        "b": "No",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "Yes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Global variable are available to all functions. Does there exist a mechanism by way of which it available to some and not to others.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Yes",
        "b": "No",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "No"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is it true that a global variable may have several declarations, but only one definition?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Yes",
        "b": "No",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "Yes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is it true that a function may have several declarations, but only one definition?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Yes",
        "b": "No",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "Yes"
    }
]